<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum on Connor Bryan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/quantum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum on Connor Bryan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>connor.bryan@zeos.system (Connor Bryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>connor.bryan@zeos.system (Connor Bryan)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2025 Connor Bryan. All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/quantum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Quantum Circuit Simulator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-quantum-circuit-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>connor.bryan@zeos.system (Connor Bryan)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-quantum-circuit-simulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching quantum mechanics, especially around quantum computing and I&amp;rsquo;ve been following a textbook on quantum machine learning. After using Python libraries like Cirq for the creation of circuits, I had the thought of creating a library in a language  I enjoy using like Rust. The goal of the first draft of the simulator was to create a simple Bell state circuit. This project has a bunch of parts;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Algorithms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/quantum-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>connor.bryan@zeos.system (Connor Bryan)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/quantum-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I picked up a textbook in Quantum Machine learning with python as it sounded interesting, and after finishing my Msc in Physics i felt like now was the time to get into it. In the textbook the author introduces the &amp;ldquo;Qubit&amp;rdquo;, a probabilistic bit that can be either a 1, 0 or a superposition between the two. Think of Schrodinger cat; The cat is either alive or dead, but until you open the box it is in a mixture of the two states. These quantum effects are what give us the phenomena of the double slit experiment where electrons can seem to go through both holes at once and there is a great video explaining this by Veritasium on YouTube (&lt;a
  href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qJZ1Ez28C-A%29&#34;
    target=&#34;_blank&#34;
  &gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qJZ1Ez28C-A)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
